How can my husband quit smoking?
I've been married for 10 months.
My husband is a smoker.
My father smoked for over 40 years,
so I know how hard it is to quit smoking.
So I try not to urge him to quit first.
But now that we're married
and we're thinking of having kids,
he's thinking of quitting.
People around him also urge him to quit,
so he claims he'd quit
along with his colleagues.
And yet only a few days later
he'd have withdrawal symptoms.
He'd say extreme things like
life isn't enjoyable
and would head out
to buy cigarettes again.
Earlier on in our marriage,
I was disappointed
in his lack of determination.
But considering it's an addiction,
there's not much I can do for him.
I'd ask if he'd want
to try nicotine patches,
he'd claim his skin is
too sensitive for them.
I'd ask if he'd want to try e-cigarettes,
he'd claim he can quit without them.
And yet he fails to quit smoking
even before the day passes.
I'd look at him thinking
'He failed again'.
For that he gets annoyed at the way
I look at him as if he is weak.
So now I'm not sure
if I should constantly nag him,
or just watch him.
Smoking is a social issue nowadays.
I'd like to hear your thoughts on
how he can quit smoking
without us hurting each others feelings.
Is it not better to have a husband
that smokes than one that gets drunk
and throws up and gets abusive?
Smoking is better.
(Sunim) Then consider it fortunate
that he's not a drunk.
Smoking is bad but it hurts oneself
more than others, does it not?
(Questioner) It does.
Drinking harms oneself but hurts others
even more than smoking does.
While not ideal, take it as fortunate.
Think to yourself, 'He doesn't
have other hobbies, I should let him be'.
(Questioner) What if he drinks too?
Drinking is okay as long as
he doesn't behave badly while drunk.
If he drinks casually,
let him be.
(Questioner) Is that so?
It's your husband's personal preference.
So should I accept
smoking as a personal preference?
I shouldn't urge him to quit?
(Sunim) No, you shouldn't.
Okay. Thank you.
(Sunim) Just let him be. If you
continue urging him to quit constantly
and he can't, you'll start
questioning his character
rather than smoking
itself being the issue.
"He's not much of a person."
"He's such a loser."
"He can't even quit smoking."
You'll keep raising demeaning
thoughts about him in your head.
Do you understand what I'm saying?
(Questioner) Yes
If you treat your husband
as a pathetic person,
you also become a pathetic person
that has to live with him.
What happens once you have a baby?
Your child becomes
a pathetic child of a pathetic father.
Hence urging him too much
about quitting smoking
no longer becomes an issue of smoking.
You'll start looking at him
as worthless. Do you understand?
People can smoke.
Yes it's not good for your health
but don't we do many things
that are bad for our health?
People do many worse things to themselves.
Hence just accept him as is.
What did I say we should do of others?
Understand them.
(Sunim) Understand and accept them.
It is the basic principle.
(Sunim) Just let it go.
But aside from your own preference,
is quitting not better
for your husband's health?
(Questioner) It's better.
(Sunim) It's better for him, right?
Then motivate him to quit smoking.
While internally accepting the fact
that he can continue smoking,
motivate him to quit on the outside.
You mentioned something about a patch?
(Questioner) Yes
You can put it on him
while he's sleeping, you see?
(Questioner) Yes
Keep bothering him like this.
Keep bothering him while you're
comfortable in your own mind. Okay?
(Questioner) Yes
At the very least,
don't allow smoking indoors
so he'll have to smoke outside
when it's cold during winter.
Don't be fretful,
just smile and say
"They say smoking is bad
for the baby you know..."
Say it nicely and kick him out,
do you understand?
Yes
(Sunim) You can say things like "I saw
men squatting on the street smoking,
(Sunim) they looked so shabby".
(Sunim) Stimulate him like that,
do you get it?
(Questioner) Yes
If he can't quit himself,
you should help him quit.
Saying "Your resolutions only last days",
"You have no willpower" is belittling.
(Sunim) Do you understand?
(Questioner) Yes.
You shouldn't belittle him.
If you insist he should quit smoking,
your husband looks bad
to you when he can't.
Instead, think that it's okay
even if he can't quit.
But playfully help him until he can.
If you continue doing this,
your husband will give in
to your playful games.
Be in such a mindset
if you want him to quit smoking.
Don't argue and fight saying
"You loser, you can't even quit smoking?"
It will only make you suffer.
Why suffer over your husband smoking?
I shouldn't
(Sunim) You shouldn't.
There is another way.
(Sunim) When he's about to
wake up in the morning,
(Sunim) light a handful of cigarettes
in his room. Do you get it?
Light them all up and put them
on an ashtray so they can burn.
Then your husband will wake up
suffocating of smoke and get irritated.
You can say, "Why not
smoke all of them at once?"
Understand?
Yes.
You can say, "I felt sorry
you had to go through
the hassle of smoking them one by one.
I helped you light them all up at once."
"Since you've smoked them all,
I suppose you don't need to
smoke anymore for the day?"
Just as he's not budging,
you shouldn't budge and
even if he gets irritated and angry.
(Sunim) Do you understand?
(Questioner) Yes.
Now would you also not have to
go through a bit of smoke for this?
(Questioner) I would.
(Sunim) Yes, you would.
You can light up those cigarettes
in the room and close the door behind you.
If not you may also become addicted.
So be cautious, wear a mask or something.
Be cautious and wear a mask,
yet don't nag or get cranky.
Either be okay with him smoking,
or help him quit smoking
by bothering him until he can't not quit.
You need to be clever about it.
If he gets angry, say "Oh I'm sorry.
All the cigarettes
somehow lit up all at once."
(Sunim) Can you do that?
(Questioner) Yes, I can do that.
(Audience Laughter)
(Applause)
Thank you.
And put up signs around the house
that say smoking is bad for you.
Draw skeletons on them.
How about that? Don't they
do that in western countries?
Cigarette packs all
have danger signs on them.
They say, "Tobacco is a drug".
American cigarette packs would say that.
Put up these signs around the house.
When he smokes a lot,
light up a bunch of them at once.
And see who wins in the end.
For you to be irritated and say
"Why aren't you listening to me?",
"Why can't you quit?" is for you to be losing.
Do you understand?
If you can have a huge grin
on your face even when he's angry,
it is you winning.
Shouldn't you be able to win
over your own man? You should.
You should win him with your pinky finger.